Jordan Ziegler

Gilbert, AZ 85234 jordanzeeg@gmail.com (626) 232-2721

I am a software developer with experience in the full stack development of a web application. I graduated from California Baptist University with a degree in Electrical and Computer Engineering. I have created dynamic front-end applications using Angular, Bootstrap, and TypeScript. In addition, I have created applications that utilize Servlets and Spring to transfer data from the front end to the back end. I have used SQL, Hibernate, and Spring Data to manage data in an Oracle database.

You can see a sample of my work at https://github.com/jordanzeeg/

You can see an angular app I made on http://jordanziegler.com/

Work Experience

Application Development Engineer

HCL Technologies - Chandler, AZ September 2021 to Present

I updated a UI program in TouchDesigner that showcased a program called ControlFlag utilizing data from a log file to demonstrate the functionality of the program. Shortly thereafter I began working on a program to showcase security features through a speech recognition program that simulates federated learning. I developed from scratch the angular UI that calls to a node.js server for speech recognition data. This UI in addition to accepting audio data for speech recognition purposes uses threejs, a javascript library, to provide a 3-dimensional graphic interpretation of how federated learning works amidst the security protections. I found and implemented for this purpose a trainable open source machine learning model which I got working, updated, and trained to provide more accurate results to the UI.

• Technologies used: Angular, NodeJS, Javascript, Typescript, CSS, HTML, TouchDesigner, Python

Zoho Developer

My Credit Guy - Gilbert, AZ January 2021 to August 2021

- Continuously research, design, document, and modify software specifications throughout the CRM production life cycle
- Create new and enhance existing components on the ZOHO platform using tools like Java C#
- Build extensions/widgets for the CRM platform using HTML, CSS JavaScript
- Produce clean, well-documented, efficient, and standards-compliant components with an eye towards performance optimization
- Write secure code and exercise good judgment in handling sensitive data
- Embrace emerging CRM standards while promoting best practices
- Improve quality through application of TDD practices
- Maintain a high awareness of industry issues and trends, particularly concerning accessibility usability, and emerging technologies; keep team members informed as appropriate, with a view to incorporating these in future projects

- Write technical software requirements as needed
- Evaluate other CRM developer code quality and provide input for performance evaluations
- Understand client short and long-term goals and recommending a solution
- Comfortable troubleshooting critical production issues
- Integrating designs, flows, and processes
- Pay attention to software development process practiced by the team and help improve it, so we deliver products on time with quality following an agile approach
- Foster a culture of continuous improvement by learning, applying, and educating team on software best practices

Software Engineer

Revature - Bentonville, AR March 2019 to August 2020

While working for Revature I was contracted to work for Sam's Club on their NextGen POS project. NextGen POS is a web application that utilizes javascript and the dojo toolkit to create, manage, and complete transactions for the purpose of sales. This project uses Java and JSON objects to communicate with various services to get data to provide information and interact with the customer.

- Examined and repaired errors in Javascript files.
- Examined and repaired errors in CSS.
- Made CSS changes in line with existing documentation of graphics
- Developed new Dojo modules using HTML, CSS, Javascript and
- Dojo functionalities.
- Support Dojo modules with Java functionality to display information
- Use Java to send/receive information from backend services.
- Generated CSS to follow Sam's Club thematic.
- Created Splunk dashboards to monitor data of test units.

Google expert

Best Buy - Yorba Linda, CA August 2018 to March 2019

The Google expert is responsible for delivering an end to end Google experience across the entirety of the Google ecosystem. This Google expert achieves sales targets across units, revenue, margin, and solutions and ensures that no customers are left unserved or underserved, providing velocity, full service, and solutions support to customers. The expectation is to build quality relationships with retail customers while providing them with relevant and memorable product demonstrations. The Google expert takes complex technology and makes it simple for clients to understand and see unique value. The google expert is also responsible for developing relationships, coaching, and training with their store; sharing their vast knowledge of the Google ecosystem with sales consultants throughout the store.

Geek Squad Consultation Agent

Best Buy/Geek Squad - Yorba Linda, CA July 2017 to August 2018

Consultation agents listen to client's needs to discern and troubleshoot the issues they had with their electronic devices. An emphasis on consistency and expediency is placed in order to provide them with an understanding of what the best solution is to solve their technical issues and the next steps we would take to provide a complete and lasting solution.

Freelance Web Developer

Camfel - Irvine, CA

January 2017 to June 2017

Developing websites using ruby on rails based on specifications from the clients to create a search engine optimized website that fits their needs and desires.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Electrical and Computer Engineering

California Baptist University

2012 to May 2015

Skills

- Javascript (2 years)
- CSS (3 years)
- HTML (2 years)
- C++ (2 years)
- Labview (1 year)
- VHDL (Less than 1 year)
- Android (1 year)
- Unity (3 years)
- Matlab (1 year)
- Autocad (2 years)
- HTML5 (2 years)
- Bootstrap (1 year)
- Java (3 years)
- JSON (1 year)
- Git (3 years)
- MySQL (1 year)
- AWS (1 year)
- User Interface (UI) (2 years)
- REST (Less than 1 year)
- APIs (1 year)
- SQL (2 years)
- CI/CD (2 years)
- GitHub
- MVC
- Angular (1 year)
- Splunk (1 year)
- Agile